Teruasa Oda broke into Gungnir's secret base,
织田照朝悄悄潜入 永恒之枪的秘密据点
and discovered their plan
并发现了他们的计划
to collect all 99 keys and take over the world.
他们要集齐99把恶魔钥匙 然后主宰世界
You'll be like a lamb to the slaughter before him.
在他面前 你就是待宰的羔羊
We're all being used by Gungnir.
我们都被永恒之枪利用了
The Guide has arrived.
有请引领者大人
Father.
父亲
Is it really true?
那是真的吗？
You're going to kill everyone but the winner?
你们要杀掉 除获胜者以外的所有人？
The time has come to tell you everything about the tournament.
差不多该跟你们介绍 整个锦标赛的全貌了
The winner of the qualifier for group B,
在B组资格赛中获胜的选手
which will be Teruasa Oda or Akira Mori,
即织田照朝或毛利明
will fight the winners of groups A and C.
将对战A组和C组的获胜选手
Whoever is victorious
在对决中获胜的选手
will get their hands on 49 keys.
将获得所有人的49把钥匙
As I mentioned before, the winner will get a special prize.
我之前说过 获胜者还有额外的奖励
The chance to go up against Our Guide.
那就是和我们的引领者大人一比高下
If you can beat him,
如果你们能获胜
including the keys in our possession,
那么包括我们拥有的钥匙在内
you will win a grand total of 99 keys.
99把钥匙将全部归获胜者所有
So even if we win, we'll be killed if The Guide beats us.
即使获得了冠军 如果输给引领者 我们还是会被杀
So we will all be slaughtered in the end.
所以结局是所有人都会被杀吗？
The chance to fight The Guide is an honor itself.
能和引领者大人对决 本身就是一种殊荣
Bullshit! I'm not doing this!
无聊 我不玩了
Do you want to die right here, right now?
真是的 你现在就想死在这里吗？
Teruasa.
照朝
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
Was this whole thing set up by you?
这一切都是你设计的吗？
We will speak alone, Teruasa.
我们单独聊 照朝
This time tomorrow, we'll all be dead.
明天这个时候 我们都会被杀死
Listen, we have to get off this island.
我们一起逃离这个岛吧
How?
怎么逃？
It's an uninhabited island.
这是个无人岛
If we can get across the sea somehow…
我们想办法渡海离开
It's pointless.
行不通
Gungnir's troops will be waiting to attack us from the shore.
在海上待命的永恒之枪部队 会攻击我们
The chance of making it out of here safely is 0%.
安全逃跑的成功率几乎为零
This all started on that day thirteen years ago.
这一切始于13年前的那一天
INORU HOSHIN ARCHAEOLOGIST
（崩心祷 考古学家）
It's a true pleasure to meet you,
能见到大名鼎鼎的织田会长
the famous Oda Group chairman.
我荣幸之至
How did you come to know that I have a devil key in my possession?
你怎么知道我有恶魔钥匙？
I believe that those chosen to be key owners
我相信被选为钥匙持有者的人
have a certain mission to fulfill.
都身负使命
I have been searching for someone who can share that mission.
我一直在寻找能够实现使命的人
A mission?
使命？
To save the world.
那就是拯救世界
This is my plan, and all the information on the keys.
这是我的计划和有关钥匙的所有信息
I'd be extremely grateful for your help.
请织田会长务必助我一臂之力
At first, I thought it was just some unrealistic fantasy.
一开始 我觉得这只是一种空想
But now I believe that by using the key's power,
但是我后来认识到 利用恶魔钥匙…
a creation beyond human comprehension,
…这种超乎人类智慧的创造 所发挥的力量
we can change the world.
我们可以改变世界
His claims were remarkably similar
他表达的主张
to my fears about the state of the world.
和我对世界的担忧几乎一致
The moment I learned of his plans,
在了解他的计划那一刻
I felt a ray of light in my heart.
我的心好像照进了一道光
Eventually, I joined Hoshin,
最终我与崩心合作
disappeared by faking my own death,
自导自演了一场假死 消失在世人眼中
-and founded Gungnir. -Dad! Dad!
-然后创建永恒之枪 -爸爸
Desire is what leads humans into conflict.
人类因为欲望而纷争不断
We live in an absurd world.
我要给这个不合理的世界
I will bring an end to it,
划上一个句号
and create a new order.
并建立新秩序
A new order?
新秩序？
I will remold this world
我会将这个世界
into a better one.
打造成一个更好的世界
What gives you the right to do that?
这就是你所谓的正义吗？
It's not my right.
不是正义
It is my moral duty.
是大义
Moral duty?
大义？
How can you say that?
这算什么大义？
Even if we need to halve the world's population,
即使世界人口会减少一半
we will see the plan through to the end.
我们也要将这个计划执行到底
Father.
父亲
Should you be concerned about other people at a time like this?
你还有余力担心别人？
You need to focus
现在你该关心的是
on tomorrow's tournament final.
明天的决赛
How can you be so calm?
你怎么能这么淡漠？
If I lose,
如果我输了
I'll be killed.
我会被杀死
Teruasa…
照朝…
As my son…
作为我的儿子…
Prove to me that you can emerge victorious.
你要战胜这个考验
Teruasa?
照朝？
Senya.
潜夜
You're a wreck.
你看起来真狼狈
What a waste of a pretty face.
这么帅的脸都浪费了
I don't know…
我已经不知道…
what to fight for anymore.
为什么而战斗了
Terurin,
小照照
since the day we lost our families,
自从我们失去家人的那一天起
we've both been living with a hole in our hearts.
我们的心就被划开了一个洞
All of the fun,
所有的快乐
happiness,
开心
and joy in my life slipped away from me.
和幸福全都离我而去
But when I met you…
但当我遇见你时…
I felt the ache in my heart beginning to mend.
我感觉那个洞在开始愈合
It makes me laugh.
很好笑吧？
Everyone's been worried,
大家都很担心你
searching for you all night.
一整晚都在找你
Even though their own lives are about to be snuffed out.
尽管他们的性命 很可能会在今天终结
Terurin…
小照照…
Our game isn't over yet.
我们的比赛还未结束
There's still something we can do.
一定还有我们能做的事
Shall we?
走吧？
Here we are!
嗨
Ta-da.
来了
Teruasa.
照朝
Thank goodness you're okay.
你没事 太好了
I'm sorry for worrying you all.
对不起 让大家担心了
You can say that again.
确实该说对不起
Yuki was crying like crazy.
悠季为你哭得一塌糊涂
It's true!
对
Well, never mind!
好啦
Terurin is filled with remorse.
小照照已经反省了
He'll fight extra hard today to make up for it.
他今天会全力应战 将功补过的
Fight? You mean the final round?
应战？你是说决战吗？
I have something I need to discuss with you.
关于这件事 我有话要跟大家说
I'll get loads of views with this.
我会收获很多播放量
You're too cute. My view count is gonna go through the roof.
你太可爱了 什么都不干就能让播放量爆表
Let's make some money.
我们要赚大钱啦
I'm gonna be rich.
要赚大钱啦
So you're saying there's a way out of this mess?
也就是说 你有办法让我们走出这个困局？
Yes.
对
But I need your help.
但我需要你的帮助
What do you think? Will you join me?
怎么样？你愿意帮我吗？
Everything is ready.
完成了
As soon as the winner is decided, we'll launch an attack on the G20 summit.
一旦决出获胜者 我们就对20国集团发动攻击
A grand display of gunfire that will shake the whole world.
这将是一个席卷全世界的炮火盛景
What? Has something happened?
什么？怎么了？
The network's dropped. International communications are down.
网络被切断了 无法与外界取得联系
Did something happen to the radio tower?
你说什么？ 电波塔有异常吗？
Is it sealed off by the creation of an enclosed space?
它被阻隔在封闭空间里了
An enclosed space?
封闭空间？
Who would do that?
是谁干的？
Guide!
引领者
I will crush
我会粉碎
all of your ambitions.
你的所有企图
I've been watching humans since the beginning of time,
自有史以来 我见过无数人类
but it's the first time I've seen them do anything this peculiar.
但做这种怪事的人 我还是第一次遇见
This whole island has been turned into an enclosed space.
你在玩游戏的同时 竟然把一个大岛屿变成一个封闭空间
I want you to play ACMA:GAME and use the whole island for the enclosed space.
我想让你玩ACMA：GAME游戏 把整个岛变成一个封闭空间
If the island is shut off,
在封闭的空间里
Gungnir can't attack, and we can avoid playing the final.
永恒之枪无法发动攻击 我们也能避免进入决赛
It'll keep your family safe too.
这样也能守护你的家人
Let's do it.
那我试试
I don't want my family in any more danger.
我也不想让我的家人出事
I have one more request.
我还有一个请求
When you create the enclosed space,
你创造封闭空间时
make sure that only The Guide's room is left unsealed.
请不要覆盖引领者所在的房间
Shogi players have exceptional spatial awareness.
棋手拥有非凡的空间感知能力
You're the only one
这种事我能拜托的
who can do it.
就只有龙王你了
Seems you were right.
看来被您说中了
The radio tower is in an enclosed space.
电波塔被封锁在封闭空间里了
This means we can't give the order to attack G20.
这样一来 我们就无法下达命令进攻20国集团
Let's settle this one-on-one.
我们来做个了结吧
Of course.
原来如此
This must be the only area excluded from the enclosed space.
这里是唯一不包含在封闭空间的区域
This is our fate, as father and son.
这是我们父子的宿命
I accept.
我接受挑战
I'll let you fight me.
来吧
Show yourself, Gado.
出来吧 卡多
I am Gado, master of this game.
我叫卡多 是这个游戏的管理者
Let's see how pride and greed clash as they come together.
让我们欣赏一场 骄傲和欲望的较量吧
The players are Teruasa Oda
这次的游戏玩家是织田照朝
and Seiji Oda,
和织田清司
or rather, The Guide, correct?
不 应该是引领者 对吧？
Yes.
对
Exactly as you say.
你说得对
What's so funny?
有什么好笑的？
Devils have an insatiable appetite for family quarrels driven by desire.
因欲望而起的骨肉相争 我们恶魔向来百看不厌
I'm expecting a fierce showdown between father and son.
我期待能看到一场 父与子之间的激烈对决
The flames of desire ignite conflict.
欲望的火焰会点燃冲突
That's why, no matter how much luck you have, you shouldn't be greedy.
因此不论你有多幸运 你都不能贪婪
Greed is a dangerous thing.
贪婪是危险的
Teruasa Oda, what do you demand?
织田照朝 你有什么要求？
The total destruction of Gungnir.
让永恒之枪彻底毁灭
Guide, what is your demand?
引领者 你有什么要求？
I want Oda Teruasa to say farewell to his past.
我要织田照朝告别过去
Farewell to his past?
告别过去？
What does he mean?
什么意思？
Very good!
有意思
Swear your oaths.
那就宣誓吧
I will fight for my desires.
我会为欲望而战
I will triumph for my desires.
我会为欲望夺胜
-I swear on the devil.
-我向恶魔发誓
Oaths accepted.
宣言接受
Let the game begin!
这次的游戏是这个
"Word Investigation."
三词问查
Let me tell you the rules.
让我来介绍规则
Each player thinks of three words.
每个玩家各自想出三个喜欢的词语
The words must be tangible nouns
这些词必须是具体名词
that are known to both players.
并且是两个玩家都知晓的词语
The point of the game is to guess your opponent's words.
这个游戏的关键就是 通过推理猜出对方想的词
It is a turn-based game.
游戏采用轮流制
When it is your turn,
当轮到你们时
you either ask a question, or make a guess.
你们或向对方提问 或猜测答案
They must only be yes or no questions.
提问必须能够用 “正确”或“不正确”来回答
YES - NO
（正确 不正确）
I will then go through the three words one by one,
然后我会逐一表明
confirming whether the answer is either "yes," or "no."
三个词的答案是是否正确
If the answer is not clear, I will answer with "unknown."
当答案模棱两可时 我会用“不确定”来回答
If you prefer to make a guess,
当你们要回答时
you must say the exact word the opponent decided on.
你们必须准确猜出对方想的词
The player who guesses all three of his opponent's words correctly
正确猜出对方三个词的选手
is the winner of the game!
就是这个游戏的胜者
Furthermore, in Word Investigation,
另外 在“三词问查”游戏里
the players can consult with a friend by using a doll.
玩家可以使用人偶 和一名同伴商量答案
Naturally, it is otherwise forbidden
当然 除了被选中的同伴外
for friends to offer hints to players.
其他在场的同伴 禁止给玩家提供任何提示
Now, both players
现在有请两名选手
choose your three words.
选出你们要比试的三个词
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Did you think the Guide
你是不是以为引领者大人
was dying of some nasty disease?
重病缠身 时日无多？
It's a drug that stimulates brain function.
那是一种激活大脑的药物
The Guide's devil power
引领者大人的恶魔之力
has taken a heavy toll on his brain.
需要消耗大量脑力
It's damaged his brain?
消耗大量脑力？
Sounds like a horrible ability.
听起来这个能力很可怕
OROCHI?
大蛇？
I can't analyze the emotion on The Guide's face.
我无法根据引领者的表情 分析出任何情绪
Write your words on the stone slabs.
在石板上写下你们的词语
As usual, he works quickly.
他的动作还是那么快
The Guide is abnormally intelligent.
引领者的知识量非比寻常
I need to think of words we both know, but are difficult to guess.
我需要想出我们都知晓 但难以猜中的词
Know what this is? It's called a "bread clip."
知道这是什么吗？这叫面包袋夹
Heard of it?
听说过吗？
I'll go with that for the first word.
第一个词就选这个
As for the last two…
至于其余两个…
Teruasa,
照朝
shall we make a separate bet?
我们再向恶魔打个赌吧？
A bet?
打赌？
If I get a correct guess,
如果我猜对了
you give me your earring.
你就把耳钉给我
Fine.
可以
What do you want from me?
你想跟我要什么吗？
I don't need anything.
我什么都不想要
With that, let Word Investigation begin!
那么“三词问查”现在开始
First, Teruasa Oda,
首先 织田照朝
declare whether you wish to ask a question, or make a guess.
你需要宣布要提问还是回答
I'll ask a question.
我要提问
He chose question first.
他选择了先进行提问
The Guide and Teruasa must know a huge amount of the same words.
照朝和引领者都知晓的词语有很多
They both need to narrow it down somehow.
他们要怎么缩小范围呢？
There are two types of questions.
提问的类型有两种
Broad category questions,
一种是确定大分类的提问
and smaller questions, limited to something specific.
一种是有针对性的细节提问
Both types of question are important.
两种提问类型都非常重要
First, I should find the broad category,
我首先要提大分类的问题
and then narrow it down.
缩小正确答案的范围
Here's my question.
这三个词
Is it a living thing?
有生命吗？
The answers are…
答案是…
NO - NO - NO
（不正确 不正确 不正确）
All answers are, "no".
全都是“不正确”
Okay. Good start.
很好 是个不错的开始
It's a good thing all three had the same answer.
三个答案都相同是好事
If it was a mix of "yes" and "no,"
如果答案混杂着“正确”和“不正确”
it would be hard to narrow down with the next question.
接下来就很难提问了
Next it's The Guide's turn.
接下来轮到引领者
Question.
我要提问
Is it a living thing?
它们有生命吗？
I knew he'd ask the same thing.
他果然会这样问
By asking the same question, he doesn't give anything away.
问同样的问题可以避免暴露信息
But…
但是…
The answers are…
答案是…
YES - YES - NO
（正确 正确 不正确）
The answer is "yes," for the blue and red stone slabs.
红色和蓝色石板显示“正确”
But the answer is "no," for the white slab.
白色石板显示“不正确”
You did it. A split answer.
太好了 答案不一致
It's only a marginal difference,
织田照朝在第一轮占据了优势
but Teruasa Oda has the upper hand.
虽然这个优势不大
Next it's Teruasa Oda's turn.
接下来轮到织田照朝
None of words written on the stone slabs
绿色、黄色和黑色石板的答案
are living things.
都是没有生命
I can exclude people, animals, and plants.
我可以排除人、动物和植物
But that changes if it's used for cooking.
但如果是食物 那就不一样了
Like beef, for example,
比如牛肉
or pork,
猪肉
or tuna, when it's used for sashimi.
或金枪鱼生鱼片
Surely they aren't living things either.
它们也属于“没有生命”
I'll ask a question.
我要提问
As far as I would know,
根据一般常识
is it something people eat?
它们是人能吃的东西吗？
The answers are…
答案是…
"Yes," for green and black, but "no," for yellow.
绿色“正确” 黄色“不正确” 黑色“正确”
A split answer.
答案不一样
The green and black words can be eaten, but are not living things.
绿色和黑色石板的答案 表明可以食用 并且没有生命
The yellow one can't be eaten, and isn't a living thing.
黄色石板的答案表明 不可食用且没有生命
The Guide knows that
引领者知道
the red and blue are living things,
红色和蓝色石板的答案表明有生命
but the white isn't.
白色石板的答案表明无生命
How is he going to attack?
他会对哪个发起进攻呢？
A living thing.
有生命的包括
An animal, plant, human.
动物、植物和人
But it's not likely to be a person.
但人的可能性很低
Someone you both know would be too easy to narrow down.
两人都认识的人不多 太容易锁定目标了
Unless he was bold enough to choose that on purpose?
除非他十分大胆 故意选了共同认识的人
The Guide's turn.
轮到引领者了
Are the red and blue words people?
红色石板和蓝色石板 写的是人名吗？
You haven't changed, Teruasa.
你还是没变 照朝
Ever since you were a child, when you have something to hide,
从小时候起 当你想隐瞒什么时
you always pull that face.
总是露出这样的表情
Question.
我要提问
Are they people?
他们是人类吗？
The answers are…
答案是…
red and blue, "yes." White, "no."
红色和蓝色“正确” 白色“不正确”
Deary me,
哎呀
he's totally seen through him.
他完全看穿了照朝
I'd expect nothing less.
果然啊
Players are allowed to ask each other questions directly.
玩家可以直接向对方提问题
You let your guard down, Teruasa.
你大意了 织田照朝
This is the true strength of The Guide, leader of Gungnir.
这就是永恒之枪引领者的真正实力
Forget that. This is not the time to be weak.
不行 现在不能软弱
First I'll narrow down the question.
首先我要缩小问题范围
A question that applies to all three words.
提一个对绿色、黄色和黑色 都适用的问题
Humans tend to only pay attention to things that relate to their own lives.
人容易忽略自己生活范围以外的事物
Time to verify that notion.
那我就验证一下
Question.
我要提问
Do they exist
它们是
within Japan?
日本国内存在的事物吗？
The answers are…
答案是…
"yes," for all three.
全部正确
That question really paid off.
答案都是“正确” 太好了
He's ruled out loads of options.
这样就排除了很多选项
The Guide's turn next.
接下来轮到引领者
Question.
我要提问
Is it something Teruasa has touched before?
照朝碰触过他们吗？
The answers are…
答案是…
"yes," for all.
全部都是“正确”
Shit, he's good at this.
该死 他果然很强
The red and blue are living things.
红色和蓝色都有生命
They're people that Teruasa Oda has touched.
他们都是织田照朝碰触过的人
The white is also something Teruasa has touched.
白色也是照朝碰过的事物
The Guide should try to figure out the white one first.
引领者大人可以借此缩小 白色石板的答案范围
Teruasa Oda, it's your turn.
接下来轮到织田照朝
Is it generally sold for less than 10,000 yen in Japan?
它们在日本的卖价 一般在一万日元以内吗？
Green and Yellow are, "yes." Black is, "no."
绿色和黄色“正确” 黑色“不正确”
Is it something I've eaten?
它们是我吃过的食物吗？
All are, "no."
全部是“不正确”
Is it available in Japan for less than 1,000 yen?
它们在日本 可以用不超过一千日元买到吗？
"Yes," for all.
全部是“正确”
Does it fit inside a cube with sides one meter long?
它们能装进边长为一米的立方体吗？
Is it a tool?
它们是工具吗？
Green, "no,"
绿色“不正确”
yellow, "unknown," black, "no."
黄色“不确定” 黑色“不正确”
Does it fit in a cube with sides 10 cm long?
它们能装进 边长为十厘米的立方体吗？
Red, "no," blue, "no," white, "yes."
红色“不正确” 蓝色“不正确” 白色“正确”
We have a lot of information to go on.
现在收集到了很多信息
First, the green is something you can eat for under 1,000 yen.
首先绿色的答案 是一千日元以内能吃的东西
It's most likely a food item.
它很可能是一种食物
The yellow is under 1,000 yen,
黄色的答案也在一千日元以内
but you can't eat it,
但不能食用
and the answer for whether it's a tool is, "unknown."
至于它是否是工具 答案是未知
But what does that even mean?
但“未知”是什么意思？
Something that exists within nature?
会是自然界存在的东西吗？
A natural object?
会不会是自然物？
Yeah.
对
For example, trees can be sold as firewood.
比如树木可以卖作木柴
So it's not originally a tool, but it can be used as one.
它原本不是工具 但可以用作工具
So the answer is "unknown."
所以答案是未知
Yeah, that seems a likely scenario.
确实很有可能是自然物
But the information we have on the black one is strange.
但最神秘的是黑色
You can eat it,
它可以食用
and it's not sold for under 10,000 yen,
售价一般不低于一万日元
but you can get it for less than 1,000 yen.
但可以花不到一千日元买到
The important word is, "generally."
对于黑色石板的答案 最重要的是“一般”这个词
It's not generally sold,
一般情况下 它不按这个价格出售
but if you want to, you can get it for less than 1,000 yen.
但是想买的话 花不到一千日元就可以买到
That's it…
有了
Perhaps a specially prepared food…
它有可能是一种特别制作的食物
Question.
我要提问
Did it exist on Earth
它们在人类诞生以前
before mankind?
就存在于地球上吗？
That's a good question.
好问题
Yes. Typical Terurin.
对 果然是小照照
What do you mean?
为什么这样说？
If the answer to green is "yes,"
如果绿色是“正确”
he can rule out prepared meals and processed food.
他就可以排除料理和加工食品了
If yellow is "yes,"
如果黄色是“正确”
he can confirm that it's a natural object.
照朝可以确定它是自然物
Right, Ui?
对吧 初？
Yes.
对
It also helps with the black.
这也有利于破解黑色石板的答案
Since it's something edible,
因为它可以食用
it'll be useful to know if it was around before mankind.
那么知晓它是否 在人类诞生以前存在就非常有用
Now for the answers.
答案是…
Green, "yes," yellow, "yes," and black, "no."
绿色“正确” 黄色“正确” 黑色“不正确”
Yes. Exactly what we wanted.
太好了 正合我们的意
The green is a natural food,
绿色是天然食物
the yellow is a natural object,
黄色是天然物品
and the black is an artificial food, right?
黑色是人工食品 对吧？
Looks like it.
是啊
Getting closer.
接近正确答案了
Teruasa, you can do it.
照朝 加油
I've narrowed most of it down.
范围缩小得差不多了
But I'm still at a disadvantage.
但是情况依然对我不利
The Guide discovered that the red and blue answers are people.
引领者知晓了红色和蓝色的答案是人
Now what?
怎么办？
Will he chase after the white?
他会从白色石板入手吗？
NOT A LIVING THING - NOT HUMAN
（无生命 不是人类）
TERUASA HAS TOUCHED IT THE GUIDE HASN'T EATEN IT
（照朝碰触过 引领者没吃过）
FITS INTO A 1 METER AND A 10 CENTIMETER CUBE
（可装进一米和十厘米立方体）
Guide, your turn.
现在轮到引领者
Question.
我要提问
Is it a tool?
它们是工具吗？
The answers are…
答案是…
red "no," blue, "no," yellow, "yes".
红色“不正确” 蓝色“不正确” 白色“正确”
He still can't identify them.
他还没有完全确定答案
It's going to be difficult now.
从现在开始变得棘手了
Teruasa Oda, it's your turn.
现在轮到织田照朝
It's also getting harder for me.
我也开始进退两难
What should I ask?
要怎么提问？
Gado, I want to use a doll.
卡多 我要使用人偶
Understood.
了解
Senya.
潜夜
Do you remember the promise you made to me?
小照照 你还记得我们之前的约定吗？
Promise?
约定？
I have three favors.
你要答应我做三件事
I can ask for anything I want.
不论我提什么要求都不能拒绝
As for my final request,
最后一个要求
I'll save it until later for fun.
等我以后想玩的时候再提
Here's my request.
现在我要行使权利了
Let me play one turn?
这一轮按我说的来提问吧？
What are your chances of success?
你的成功率有多高？
Yukky and Yukarin said
我问过小悠季和小紫了
it'll never work.
她们说绝对没戏
Let me hear it.
你说说看
I've fought against superior people countless times.
我跟高高在上的人比过很多次
They have a bad habit.
他们有一个毛病
They want to win by pulling off an astounding victory.
那就是总想取得压倒性的胜利
The most amazing victories
最具压倒性的胜利
use methods an ordinary person would never try.
就是用普通人不会选择的方式取胜
Maybe that's what The Guide is after?
说不定引领者也想这样赢你
Terurin, that's my third demand.
小照照 这就是我的第三个要求
Okay.
好
Question.
我要提问
Is it within this enclosed space?
它们在这个封闭空间里吗？
The answers are…
答案是…
all "yes."
全部是“正确”
You did it!
太好了
What a painful blow.
这是致命的一击
We've gotta win now.
我们要赢了
The Guide's words are all things in this room.
引领者的答案全在这个房间里
He's totally cornered.
他被逼上绝境了
In the end, Senya is the key player.
上杉潜夜果然是个关键人物
Write your words on the stone slabs.
在石板上写下你们的词语
Teruasa,
照朝
one of your answers
你的一个答案
relates to an exchange you had with Senya Uesugi.
与你和上杉潜夜的对话有关
He told you a word that you didn't know before.
他跟你说了一个你没听过的词
You thought it would be more difficult…
你选择用这个词
for me to guess such a word.
以为这样会降低我猜中的几率
But…
但是…
I'm afraid you were wrong.
那是白费力气
Unleash my power.
启动恶魔之力
Falcon Kujo.
猎鹰九条
FALCON KUJO
（猎鹰九条）
What's this?
哎呦
This is so cool.
这名字真酷
I'll make a guess.
我要回答
The word on the white stone slab is…
白色石板上的词是…
"bread clip".
面包袋夹
The answer is…
答案…
BREAD CLIP
（面包袋夹）
Correct!
正确
You're kidding.
难道…
He traced my memory
他回顾我的记忆
and found the answer.
找到了答案？
Your memory?
记忆 ？
Isn't that cheating?
这种能力也太欺负人了
He's a monster.
他就是个怪物
So, Teruasa…
那么 照朝
Just as we agreed, I'll take that earring.
按照我们打的赌 你要将耳钉给我
You always wear those earrings.
你总是戴这副耳钉
That's right. They're my special ones.
没错 它们是妈妈的宝贝
They're the first ever gift your father gave to me.
这是爸爸送给妈妈的第一份礼物
What was that for? They were Mom's－
你干什么？那是妈妈的…
It's like I said!
我说了
Saying farewell to your past means destroying who you were before.
跟过去告别就是摧毁原来的自己
If I guess the next one correctly, I want your watch.
如果我猜对下一个词 我要你的手表
As I have said many times,
我说过很多次
if you spill even one drop of water, you lose.
只要有一滴水溢出水缸 你们就输了
What an honor it is.
真是荣幸啊
To think I get to play ACMA:GAME against Dragon King Mori.
我竟然能跟敬仰的毛利龙王 玩ACMA：GAME恶魔游戏
He's only playing with you to buy time.
他跟你玩是为了争取时间而已
Quiet.
嘘
Mori, it's your turn next.
接下来轮到毛利先生
-Akira! -Are you okay?
-老公 -龙王 你没事吧？
Yes.
没事
I didn't know it would be this difficult
没想到创造一个特殊的封闭空间
to create a specific enclosed space.
竟然这么难
But I have to keep the game going as long as possible.
但是我必须拖延下去
Every second counts.
一分一秒都要争取
Wait.
嗯？
Are you deliberately stalling to stop the game from finishing?
难道你在故意拖延时间？
How impertinent.
真是不知深浅
Our secret's out.
被看穿了
Let me just say this.
我这么说吧
In the event that a player dies,
如果玩家在游戏中死亡
the enclosed space will remain closed for eternity.
封闭空间将永远无法解除
Keep calm, Teruasa.
冷静 照朝
He's only guessed one correctly.
他现在只猜对了一个词
I need to make a guess too.
现在我也只能猜词了
I know the most about the yellow one.
首先信息最齐全的是黄色石板
It's not a living thing,
它没有生命
it can't be eaten,
不可以食用
you can get it for under 1,000 yen.
可以花不到一千日元买到
I don't know whether it's a tool.
不确定是不是工具
It existed on Earth before mankind.
在人类诞生以前 它就存在于地球上
It's a natural object that is definitely in this room.
而且它肯定是 存在于这个房间里的自然物
The obvious ones
最显眼的是
would be stone or wood.
石头和木头
That must be it…
有了
I'll make a guess.
我要回答
The word on the yellow stone slab is…
黄色石板上的词是…
stone.
石头
Now for the answer…
答案是…
STONE
（石头）
Correct!
正确
-We've caught up! -That was amazing, Teruasa.
-追上来了 -好厉害 照朝
But how did he know?
但他是怎么知道的？
Don't ask me.
我也不知道
But I'm still the one who's cornered.
但我现在仍然被逼得很紧
He's already narrowed down the red and blue a lot.
剩下的红色和蓝色 他已经极大地缩小了范围
The red and blue are living things.
红色和蓝色的答案都表明有生命
They're both people that Teruasa has touched.
他们都是照朝碰触过的人
But wait.
但是想一想
The fact that it's a living thing…
说到有生命…
Here's my question.
这三个词
-I got that information… -Is it a living thing?
-我通过问同样的问题… -有生命吗？
…by copying Teruasa's first question.
…得到了“有生命”的信息
What if
这会不会
that was a trap from the very beginning?
在一开始就是个陷阱
Here's my question.
我要提问
Are the red and blue words
红色和蓝色的答案
someone who is currently dead,
在生前是一位故人
a person who no longer exists?
现在已不在人世 对吗？
The answers are…
答案是…
"yes," for both red and blue.
红色和蓝色都是“正确”
Just as I suspected.
果然如我所料
That can't be.
怎么可能？
The red and blue are living things.
红色和蓝色不是都表明有生命吗？
How does that work?
这是怎么回事？
If we're talking about right now, the dead are no longer living.
以现在的视角来看 死去的人是没有生命的
But they were living things once.
但他们曾经有过生命
Teruasa,
照朝
your answer recognizes the dead as "living things."
你以已故之人的名字作为选词
You misled me into thinking of someone who is alive, just as I am now.
并故意误导我 让我以为这是一个活生生的人
He's seen through my plan.
他看穿了我的计划
There's no time to waste.
没有时间可以浪费了
I have to guess the green or black.
我必须猜出绿色或黑色石板的词
NATURAL FOOD ARTIFICIAL FOOD
（自然食品 人工食品）
The green and black can both be eaten.
绿色和黑色的答案都表明可以食用
They're in this room.
它们都在这个房间里
Have any of you got anything edible?
大家把手上的食品拿出来
Just candy.
全是糖果
I don't know about the black,
黑色石板的答案我不清楚
but the green is something that existed before mankind,
但绿色石板的答案 出现在人类诞生以前
so it can't be candy.
所以它不可能是糖果吧？
Earlier, I guessed stone rather than wood
我刚才选石头而不是木头
because of something Senya said to me.
是因为潜夜的话启发了我
They have a bad habit.
他们有一个毛病
They want to win by pulling off an astounding victory.
那就是总想取得压倒性的胜利
This room is full of stuff made from stone.
这个房间里几乎都是石头
The Guide was daring enough to pick something obvious.
引领者特意选择了非常显眼的东西
So perhaps he did the same for the green.
绿色石块的答案或许也是如此
Have I overlooked something?
我有没有看漏什么？
Something else edible in this room?
这个房间里还有能吃的东西吗？
It can't be a human.
答案不可能是人
Beef?
牛肉？
What you looking at?
嗯？
Surely not…
肯定不是
Teruasa Oda,
织田照朝
are you thinking of something wicked?
你在起什么坏念头？
That's it.
有了
It's an edible meat that has existed since before mankind,
它是人类诞生以前 就存在的一种食用肉类
and something that humans have now.
而且现在依然存在
A cut of meat, or organs.
比如某个部位或内脏
Tongue, liver, the neck, or heart.
舌头、肝脏、脖子或心脏
There are endless edible body parts and organs.
许多部位和内脏都可以食用
Which word would he pick to show off the most?
他会选什么来取得压倒性的胜利？
Think.
想一想
95% of Egypt is desert land.
埃及有大约95%的国土是沙漠
Back then, people called him the "beating heart of Oda Group."
以前大家都称他为织田集团的心脏
I'm going to guess.
我要回答
The green word is…
绿色石板的答案是…
heart.
心脏
The answer is…
答案…
HEART
（心脏）
…correct!
…正确
Finally! Teruasa's in the lead!
照朝终于领先了
Way to go!
太好了
Guide, it's your turn next.
接下来轮到引领者
I'll make a guess.
我要回答
The red stone slab
红色石板的答案是
is Reika Oda.
织田丽华
The answer is…
答案…
REIKA ODA
（织田丽华）
…correct!
…正确
When I think about the dead,
当我回想已逝的故人时
your mother is the first person that comes to mind.
第一个想到的就是你妈妈
Teruasa,
照朝
hand over the watch.
把手表给我
This is something I used long ago.
这是我多年以前用过的手表
Being attached to the past is a sign of weakness.
执着于过去是一种软弱的表现
Like me, you must abandon your past.
你必须像我一样抛弃过去
Why do you care what I do?
你管我做什么？
You left me when you faked your own death.
你假死并离开了我
You abandoned me.
你抛下了我
No…
不…
I've always been watching over you from afar.
我一直在远处默默守护你
I believed that one day
我相信有一天
you would come back to me.
你会回到我身边
I love you.
我爱你
You are broken, after all.
你果然很坏
This world is broken.
坏的是这个世界
Two questions correct on both sides.
两人都猜对了两个词
The person who figures out the last one wins.
猜出第三个词的人将获得胜利
Very entertaining.
有意思
Now we're getting to the heart and soul of ACMA:GAME.
现在才是 ACMA：GAME恶魔游戏的精彩时刻
Victory hasn't been decided yet,
现在胜负未定
and I'm going to win.
我会赢的
Let me tell you something.
我告诉你吧
I already have an idea
最后一个答案
what the last answer is.
我已经有头绪了
How long are you going to keep up this charade?
这个闹剧要持续到什么时候？
Date, your turn.
现在轮到伊达先生
Dragon King Mori,
毛利龙王
I have a great deal of respect for you.
你实在是令人钦佩
To maintain a huge but delicately designed enclosed space
努力维持这么宽大又精细的封闭空间
takes a huge amount of willpower.
这是多么伟大的精神啊
What are you doing?
你干什么？
You've decided to finish the game?
你决定要结束游戏了？
The winner of Pour to Limit is Akira Mori,
“入水限度”的胜者是毛利明
and the game now comes to a close.
现在游戏结束
Wait! No!
等等 不
A debt to be paid.
赌债必须清偿
Date,
伊达
what are you trying to do?
你的目的是什么？
A genius like you doesn't know?
像你这样的天才还不清楚吗？
I just
我只想
want to observe human nature.
观察人类
Asai,
浅井
you and I need to start playing ACMA:GAME right now.
你和我马上开始 玩ACMA：GAME恶魔游戏
I need to create another enclosed space.
我要再创造一个封闭空间
Akira!
老公
Dragon King!
龙王
You pushed yourself too far.
果然还是太勉强了
You don't have the strength to make another enclosed space.
你已经无力再创造一个封闭空间
Dragon King!
龙王
Akira, Akira!
老公
The enclosed space created by Mori has been terminated.
毛利创造的封闭空间消失了
No way.
不可能
What good news.
真是个好消息啊
Now when The Guide wins,
接下来如果引领者大人获得胜利
we can attack G20.
我们就能进攻20国集团了
The Guide will definitely guess next time.
引领者在下一轮一定会选择回答
If Terurin is going to win,
如果小照照想赢
he's gotta do it now.
这一轮他必须答对
The black stone slate is the only one left.
现在只剩下黑色的石板了
OROCHI.
大蛇
The information we have so far, is that it's not living,
黑色石板的信息是它没有生命
it can be eaten,
可以食用
it can't be sold for under 10,000 yen,
不能以一万日元以下的价格售卖
but you can get it for 1,000 yen.
但可以按一千日元以内的价格买到
It's not a tool,
它不是工具
and it didn't exist on Earth before mankind.
在人类诞生以前 它在地球上不存在
It's inside this enclosed space.
它存在于这个封闭空间里
But what can be edible in here and fit all those conditions?
但是在这里 符合条件的可食用物品是什么呢？
Teruasa Oda, your turn.
接下来轮到织田照朝
Gado, I want to use a doll.
卡多 我要使用人偶
Understood.
了解
Yuki.
悠季
Why me?
为什么选我？
You have a weird way of helping me relax.
和你说话时 我会不可思议地平静下来
Plus, calm analytical skills are something I'm lacking.
而且我缺乏的正是冷静分析的能力
I see.
我知道了
So,
我举个例子吧
a cheap piece of candy sold for less than 1,000 yen
一块糖果的售价不到一千日元
might be worth much more if owned by someone like Yukari.
但如果它是紫的糖果 那么它的价格可能会涨到一万日元
I'm sorry, that's all I can think of.
我能想到的只有这个了
No,
不
that's a good approach.
这是个好思路
Back then, we got Mog Chocolate sent to our house from the factory.
以前我们家里的Mog巧克力 是直接从工厂送到家的
You wouldn't exactly say that it was sold to us,
严格来说它不是卖给我们的
but we could get hold of it for less than 1,000 yen.
但我们可以按一千日元以下的价格 购买它们
Yum, Mog Chocolate.
是Mog巧克力
Yes, please.
我尝尝
Dad! Don't gobble that much!
别吃那么多 爸爸
If he wants to put on a show with an incredible victory,
如果他想取得压倒性的胜利
he'd pick a word close to my heart.
他会选择对我而言重要的东西
That's if he still remembers
如果他还记得
things that make me happy.
什么能让我感到幸福
Thank you.
谢谢
I want to make a guess.
我要回答
The word on the black stone slab is…
黑色石板上的词是…
mogmog chocolate.
Mog巧克力
The answer is…
答案…
incorrect!
不正确
Hang on!
老公 撑住啊
Shit! What should we do?
可恶 现在怎么办？
I can hear it.
我听到了
The cries of your screaming hearts.
你们内心的悲鸣
All of your hopes are devastated.
你们所有的希望都要破灭了
Game over is nearly here.
游戏马上就要结束了
Teruasa,
照朝
accept your fate.
接受你的命运吧
Teruasa Oda.
织田照朝
You're in a tight spot.
你的处境很危险
Guide, it's your turn.
现在轮到引领者
NEXT EPISODE
（下集预告）
THE FINAL CHAPTER
（大结局）
Thank you for fighting with me.
谢谢和我一起战斗
We followed you because we knew we wouldn't regret
我们跟随你是因为我们知道
whatever outcome you achieved.
无论结果如何 我们都不会后悔
Let's restore this world together.
我们一起重建这个世界吧
Look out!
当心